Guide to the Mark Bloch Postal Art Network (PAN) Archive MSS.170
Fales Library and Special Collections
Mark Bloch Postal Art Network (PAN) Archive
1978-2009
Fales Library and Special Collections
Bloch, Mark, 1956-
MSS.170
48.25 Linear Feet in 96 boxes, 8 box-binders, and 5 flat file folders.
Mark Bloch (born 1956) is an American artist and writer who uses visuals and text to explore ideas of long-distance communication. In 1978 he founded the Postal Art Network (PAN) and began to use international postal services to distribute and receive art and connect with artists, art groups, institutions, and cultural workers from all over the world. The bulk of this collection, which spans from 1971 to 2009, consists of mail art sent to Bloch by correspondents in all fifty American states and dozens of countries. Examples of mail art in this collection include objects, postcards, enclosures, xerox prints, and collages, as well as serials and announcements documenting avant-garde cultural activities in various media. Additionally, this collection also includes books, personal materials that document Bloch's life, and what was deemed "junk mail" by Bloch.
Biographical Note
Mark Bloch is an American fine artist and writer who uses visuals and text to explore ideas around long-distance communication. Bloch was born in 1956 in Würzburg, Germany, where his father was based as a soldier of the US Army, and grew up in the suburbs of Cleveland and then Akron, Ohio. Bloch attended Kent State University, where he received his B.A. degree in broadcasting. In 1977, after studying traditional art forms as well as performance and video art, Bloch discovered the international mail art network and began to correspond with key figures in that movement.
Mail art is a movement developed by Ray Johnson and the Fluxus Group in the 1950s that involves the use of the postal service for the dissemination of artwork in order to circumvent official art distribution centers such as museums, art markets, and galleries. From 1978 to 1982 Bloch lived in Southern California and supported himself by making slide shows for corporate clients in the audiovisual industry. Bloch founded the Postal Art Network (PAN) in 1978 and began to correspond with the international network of mail artists originally established by Ray Johnson, later known as the New York Correspondence School. Bloch moved to New York in 1982 and became a member of Ray Johnson's New York Correspondence School. Bloch used the international postal system as a distribution network for his art and reached out to thousands of artists and cultural workers all over the world. In 1989, Bloch began his experimental foray into the digital space when he founded Panscan, part of a text-based teleconferencing system, the first online art discussion group in New York City. Bloch continues his work with mail art and related concepts online.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions. Please contact the Fales Library and Special Collections, fales.library@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596.
Provenance
Purchased from Mark Bloch in 2005; the accession number associated with the gift is 2005.170.
Scope and Content
The Postal Art Network (PAN) Archive consists of materials amassed by Mark Bloch, the founder of PAN and participant in the mail art movement. The collection documents the evolution of the mail art, Bloch and other artists' works, national and international avant-garde cultural activities, and parts of the global arts scene throughout the 1980s, 1990s, and early 2000s. Movements and artistic styles represented include Fluxus, Neo-Dada, Neo-Futurism, and Neoism. The PAN Archive also reflects the experimental circumvention and strategic navigation of mainstream cultural institutions in favor of the Do It Yourself culture of the late 20th century. Spanning from 1971 to 2009, the majority of the items in this collection are samples of original mail art or correspondence pertaining to it, sent to Bloch by artists, art groups, and institutions in all 50 states and dozens of countries. Said items include collages, paintings, drawings, Xerox artwork, stamp artwork, and invitations for mail art project participation. There are also non-mail art periodicals, announcements and flyers he gathered for over four decades, serials, and books. Additionally, materials include personal documents and correspondence Bloch deemed junk mail.
Some items in this collection contain profanity, sexually explicit, and violent content.
Art museums -- Exhibitions.; Art and society.; Direct mail.; Collages (visual works); Fliers (printed matter); Posters.; Postcards.; Picture postcards.; Mail Art.; Zines; Correspondence.
- Series I: Mail Art and Correspondence, 1976-2009; 22.5 Linear Feet in 44 manuscript boxes, 8 box binders, and 6 oversize flat boxes.
  Scope and Content
  This series comprises the bulk of this collection and contains art, correspondence, and ephemera that resulted from Bloch's mail exchange with artists, art groups, and institutions in all 50 states and dozens of countries within the context of the Postal Art Network (PAN). The following files represent each of those countries and states and they include a list of correspondents from them. These lists are not exhaustive.
  Materials in this series span from 1971 to 2009 and include letters, Xerox artwork, postcards, zines, pamphlets, enclosures, collages, drawings, newsletters, booklets, press clippings, stickers, photographs, stamp artworks, greeting cards, flyers, and invitations for mail art project participation, and announcements documenting avant-garde cultural activities in various media. Prominent correspondents include H.R. Fricker, Anna Banana from the Fluxus Group, Robert Delford Brown, Buster Cleveland, Ed Higgins, Bill Gaglione, Sonja van der Burg, Ryosuke Cohen, Carlo Pittore and Ruggero Maggi. Furthermore, there are materials on two art projects headed by Bloch: the "Last Mail Art Show" created in 1984 and the "One World Postal Art Show" which opened in 1996.
  Arrangement
  The files in this series are arranged alphabetically by country of origin.
  - Algeria, 1983-1990 (Box 1, Folder 1, Box 86, Folder 2)
    Scope and Contents
    Correspondents include: Baubete-Friend of Larry Mullins (USA), Farida.
  - Argentina, 1983-1998 (Box 1, Folder 2, Box 88, Box 102, Folder 1)
    Correspondents include: Claudia de Rio, E.A. Vigo, Escuela de Bellas Artes, Jorge Orta, Laboratorio de Arte Integral, Municipalidad de la Plata, Vortice.
  - Australia, 1983-1992 (Box 1, Folder 3-4, Box 85, Folder 2, Box 86, Box 87, Folder 3, Binder 15, Box 89, Box 94, Folder 1, Box 102)
    Correspondents include: Cerebral Shorts, Charles Roberts (IMUURI), CIDC, Confederation of Chivalry, David Dellafiora, Emotion Pictures, Grant Price and Family, Keith Migdal (USA), Pat and Dick Larter, PC Dooley, Tibor Papp (Easy Dada), "What?" Magazine.
  - Austria, 1991-2001 (Box 1, Folder 5-6)
    Correspondents include: Manfred Wiesinger, Peter Fuchs, Prix Ars Electronica, "The Kretzer" Group.
  - Belgium, 1983-2003 (Box 1, Folder 7-11, Box 83, Folder 5, Box 84, Folder 1,5,7, Box 85, Folder 1,7, Box 87, Folder 2, Box 88, Box 89, Box 90, Box 95, Folder 1, Box 98, Box 99, Box 102, Folder 3)
    Correspondents include: Alain Neffe (Insaine Music Contact), Baudhuin Simon, Centrum voor de Kunsten Begijnhof, Charles Francois (Ratos), DeMedia, Dr. Piotr Aakoun, Geert De Decker, Guido Vermeulen, Guy Bleus, Guy de Bievre, Guy Stuckens (Mail Art Magazine), Harley, J. Gijsenbergs, Johan De Baeta, aka Quasi, Johan Van Geluwe (A.R.T), Johan Van Geluwe (Museum of Museums), José Van Der Brouke, Kristrof D'Haeseleer, aka Kristof Debris, Kunstcentrum Il Ventuno, La Drolesse, Luce Fierens, Luce Fierens and Annina Van Sebroeck, Metallic Avau (Aerosol), Noelle Michiels, Radio Panik, Rudi Wilderjans, Serge Segay (USSR) via Luce Fierens, Sjoerd Paridaen, aka Paridada, Société Anonyme, Stedelijke Akademie, Stijn Huwels, Sztuka Fabryka, Tania Desmet, Thienpont Annick, V.Z.W. De Nar.
  - Brazil, 1983-1995 (Box 2, Folder 1, Box 86, Folder 2, Box 88, Box 95, Box 102, Folder 4)
    Correspondents include: A de Araujo, Antonio Lima, Centro Cultural Sao Paulo, César Brandão, Equipe de Arte Postal, Fundacao Bienal de São Paulo, Funesc, Gilberto Prado, JKArt Gallery, Lidia Lopes Torres, Norma Campaz (JK Empreendimientos), Paulo Bruscky, Prefeitura Municipal de Santo André, Prof. Iraci S.V. da Silva (EEPG), Yeda Schmaltz.
  - Bulgaria, 1983-1991 (Box 2, Folder 2, Binder 15)
    Correspondents include: Guillermo Deisler, Vesselin Sarieff.
  - Canada, 1981-2005 (Box 2, Folder 3-9, Box 83, Folder 4, Box 84, Folder 5,7, Box 85, Folder 5, Box 86, Folder 1, Box 87, Folder 1,3, Binder 16, Box 88, Box 89, Box 90, Box 95, Folder 3, Box 98, Box 102)
    Correspondents include: Alberto Kurapel, Alex Smith, Alternative and Independent Study Program, Anna Banana, Bonnie Eng, Centre Copie-Art, Chuck Stake, Citizen X, Cony Mail Services, Counterrevolutionary Propaganda Campaign, Dale Spiers, Dick Tool Co, Dr. Mervin La Vallee, Drew Duncan (Friend of Sonja Van Der Burg), Ed Varney, Elaine M. Rounds, GX Jupitter-Larsen, Istvan Kantor (Monty Cantsin), Jacques Sainte-Marie (Cony Exit), Jim Adams (ITT Studio), Karla Cummins, Kurt Beaulieu, La Toanvinh, Laurie Muskego, Lyle Lee, Maison des Jeunes L'Imageries, ManWoman, Martine Savard, Mental Note Productions, Michael Duquette, Museo Internacionale de Neu Art (Banque du Fluxus), Nathaniel Rounds, Neoist Apt Fest, Neutral Ground, Parachute Magazine, Paul Hartal (Lyrical Conceptualist Society-Center for Art, Science, and Technology), Pig Productions, Pyramid Magazine, Re Buat, Sam's Recycle Shop, Sarah Jackson, Sensoria from Censorium, Simon Fraser University Gallery, Struts Gallery, Suzanne Nuttall, The Works Festival, University of Moncton Art Gallery, University of Waterloo, World of Artistamps (Rosie Gahlinger-Beaune).
  - Chile, 1992-1995 (Box 2, Folder 10, Binder 16, Box 101, Item 3)
    Correspondents include: Hans Braumuller, Antonio Pérez-Carest
  - Colombia, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 1, Box 89)
    Correspondents include: Rafael del Llano
  - Croatia, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 2, Box 86, Folder 3)
    Correspondents include: Svjetlana Mimica
  - Cuba, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 3, Box 102, Folder 6)
    Correspondents include: Jaqueline Mir (Banco de Ideas Z)
  - Czechoslovakia/Czech Republic, 1990-1995 (Box 3, Folder 4, Box 88, Box 102, Folder 7)
    Correspondents include: Andreas Wolf, Deti Záklandlní Skola, ER Atelier (Milan Bruchter), Ivan Preissler, Jiri Veselka, RI-EL (Frantisek Hrabla-Gibalová), Zdenek Sima.
  - Denmark, 1983-1992 (Box 3, Folder 5, Box 86, Folder 3, Binder 16, Binder 17, Box 98)
    Correspondents include: Atmosphere Controlled (Mogens Otto Nielsen), Leena Kemppi, Lomholt Formular Press, Steen Moller Rasmussen (Plagiat).
  - Dominican Republic, 1992-1993 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    Correspondents include: Direccion de Cultura (V Centenerio-Encuentro de Culturas), Roberto Accorti.
  - Egypt, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 7, Box 102, Folder 8)
    Correspondents include: Mashrabia Gallery
  - England, 1984-1990 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    Correspondents include: Barry Edgar Pilcher, Fish (Rupert Loydell), Gianni Broi (Italy), Int'l Biographical Centre, Mark Dawson, Roger Radio, Stefan Szczelkun.
  - Finland, 1985-2004 (Box 3, Folder 9, Binder 17, Box 94, Folder 2, Box 98)
    Correspondents include: Joensuun Kaupunki, Jouni Wäärakangas, Kimmo Framelius, Reima Mäkinen, Turun Kirjakahvila, Valtion Taidemuseo.
  - France, 1983-2004 (Box 3, Folder 10-12, Box 4, Folder 1-2, Box 84, Folder 4-5,7, Box 85, Folder 1, Box 86, Folder 2, Box 87, Binder 15, Binder 17, Box 88, Box 89, Box 90, Box 98, Box 102, Folder 9)
    Correspondents include: AAAA, Annick Durban, ARIAP (Ecole d'Arts Plastiques) Aristide 3108, Association Arte-Terre, Bernadette Troubat, Bruno Sourdin, Cimade, Come Together Productions, Cuffs and Collar, Daniel Daligand, Dazibao Magazine, Denis Malagna, Editions Nepe, Eric Langolff, Francois Billaw and Lucien Seul, Francois Duviver (Metro Riquet), Gilberto Prado, HAN PSI, Institut National de L'Audiovisuel (INA), Isabelle Conseil, IT Park Gallery (Taiwan), J. Rabascall, Jacques Massa, JN Laszlo, L' Assault de la Menuiserie, Le Moulin, Le Peintre Nato, Les Vraies Folies Bergères, Lon Spiegelman (USA) via Champendal, Lucien Sued, Manue and Colas Meulen, Marie Blanem, Michel Champendal, Michel Collet, Mielle Christophe (Chris P), Miriam Sharon, Mob Shop, Mr. Nanson, Office de la Culture de Marseille, P. Morice, Pascal Lenoir, Patrice Bolte, Pegase, Phillip Chlebowski, Rémy Pénard, Rene Montes, Reynald Round 2, Robert Morillo, Rodoid Koyott, Tibor Papp (Australia) via Champendal.
  - Germany, 1983-2004 (Box 4, Folder 3-8, Box 5, Folder 1-5, Box 83, Folder 2,7, Box 84, Folder 2,5, Box 85, Folder 2, Box 87, Folder 1, Binder 15, Binder 17, Box 88, Box 89, Box 90, Box 94, Folder 3, Box 97, Box 98, Box 99, Box 100, Folder 5, Box 102, Folder 10, Flat-file-folder 5 Right)
    Correspondents include: Achim Schyder, Adalbert Stifter Verein, Albrecht/d, Alexandra Holownia, Aloys Olmann, Alvaro, Andy Black (Andrej Skrbinek), Angela and Henning Mittendorf, Angela and Peter Netmail (A and P Netmail), Anne Schoon, BERM (Kollegium Bildender Künstler), Bernd Löbach, Bernhard Skopnik, Bilder für Afrika, Birger Jesch, C. Schmidt, Chris Horstmann, Christine Pinnen, Detlef Kappis, Dressler, Eberstadter Donnerkeil, Emmet Walsh (Jürgen O. Olbrich), Friedhelm Schulz, Gerd Beyer, Géza Perneczky, Ge­­sam­t­hoch­­­schu­­le Kas­­sel, Guillermo Deisler, Hans-Mwe Goehlich, Hapunkt Fix, HE Urb and V. Wohlfarth, Heike-K. Hoenig, Heino Otte, Henning Mittendorf, Herbert Prinz, Ines Ruf (Neoist Propaganda Institute), Joan Bunus, John W. Glaw, Joki, Jürgen Kierspel, Klaus Groh, Klaus Kux, Klaus Peter-Fürstenau, Litsa Spathi, Manfred Tari (Thomas), Marianne Weigelt, Markus Reichert, Martina and Steffen Giersch, Michael Fox, Monty Cantsin, Museum für Moderne Kunst Weddel, Neue Gesellschaft für Bildende Kunst, Ona Nuk, Peter Adams, Peter Below, Peter Bergner, Petra Lee, Ralf Schulze, Reinhard Nißle, Robert Rehfeldt, Roland Schefferski, Ruth Wolf-Rehfeldt, S3/KM3 Radke, Sabine Hund, Spieltour Foto, Stephen Jacob, Tacho, Tilo Block, Tim Midas, Ulrich Kattenstroth, Ulrich Tarlatt, Ulrike Weiland, Wolfgang Grossman.
  - Ghana, 1985-1991 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    Correspondents include: Ayah Okwabi, Kwabena Leboah.
  - Greece, 1983-1990 (Box 5, Folder 7, Box 86, Folder 4, Box 89, Box 90)
    Correspondents include: Alternative Gallery, Dimosthenis Agrafiotis.
  - Hungary, 1983-2002 (Box 5, Folder 8, Box 84, Folder 5, Box 85, Folder 1, Box 87, Folder 3, Box 90, Box 98, Box 102, Folder 11)
    Correspondents include: György Galántai (Artpool), Hétterony Kft., Kazimour Antal, Koppany Nartun, Kovacs Peter Balazs, LMAS (Ezsias Istuan), Pap Bela, Szilagyi Lenke, Takács Rudolf, Toth Arpad.
  - India, 1989-1993 (Box 5, Folder 9, Box 90)
    Correspondents include: C. Nachiappan (Kalakshetra Publications), Kelly. Om., Viswa Shanti Nikethana.
  - Indonesia, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 10, Box 87, Folder 2)
    Correspondents include: Wahyuni Kamah
  - Ireland, 1985-1990 (Box 5, Folder 11, Box 87, Folder 5, Box 98, Box 102, Folder 12)
    Correspondents include: Ben Allen, Cork Summer Festival, Tony Lowes.
  - Israel, 1976-1995 (Box 5, Folder 12-13, Box 90, Box 98)
    Correspondents include: Bryan Desure, Christo van der Schyff, Devra Araten, Varda Serok, Yossi Lemel.
  - Italy, 1980-2004 (Box 6, Folder 1-8, Box 7, Box 8, Folder 1, Box 83, Folder 3, 7, Box 84, Folder 5, 7, Box 85, Folder 1, 5, 7, Box 86, Folder 4,6,7,8, Box 87, Folder 1,4,5, Binder 15, Binder 17, Box 88, Box 89, Box 90, Box 91, Box 95, Folder 4, Box 96, Folder 1-2, Box 98, Box 101, Item 1, Box 102, Folder 13)
    Correspondents include: A. Girardi, AAA Edizioni, Alberto Rizzi, Aldo Trivellato, Aleph and Acidpunk and Alcoolbologna, Alessandro Aiello, Alfio Fiorentino, Alozen, Angelo Lopiano, Angelo Vitale, Anna Boschi, Antonio Sasse, Antonio Tregnagni, Ark (Arch. Melandri), Artestudio, Associazione Culturuale Musi and Muse, AUSL Le1 (Center For Treatment and Research for Eating Disorders), Bartolome Miglione, Biasin Stefano, Biblioteca Comunale Imola, Donato Bonazzi, Brain Cell-Art Strike (Alfredo Slang), Brio Mai(A)l Art-Group of Florence, Bruno Capatti, Bruno Chiarlone, Bruno Pecchioli, Bruno Pollacci (Mail Art Archive), Capuanova, Carmine Mangone, Claudio Romeo, Commune Di Senigallia, Dell'Oro Giosuè, Dino Gobbo, Emilio Morandi, Ennio Pauluzzi, Enrico Piva, Fanna Roncoroni, Fausto Ducci, Francesco Conz, Franco De Mas, Franco Vallare, Fulgor C. Silvi, Gabriele Castielli, Giacomo Cesari, Giancarlo Da Lio, Giancarlo Polití, Gianni Broi, Giorgia Malossi, Giorgio Nelva, Giovanni Fontana, Giovanni Strada, Guiseppe Crescentini, Guiseppe Gasparno, Guiseppe Perotti, Guiseppe Spennatti, "il donchisciotte"/Newsletter, Il Politecnico-Centro de Iniziativa Culturale, Istituto Superiore di Spilimbergo, Jacopo Benassi, JJ and Co. Communication Ent., Karen Eliot, Lamberto L. Caravita, Lancillotto Bellini, Livia Cases-C. Marconi 11, Luca Bruneri, Luigi Spennati, Lydia Lorenzi, Mail Art Archive-Adria ("The brain of the monster" Organization), Mail Art Centre (Scuola Media G. Perotti), Mail Art Gallery and Museum (MAGAM), Marcello Diotallevi, Maria Pia Fanna Roncoroni, Mario Grande, Massimo Pattaro, Mateo Cagnola (Mail Art Archive), Mauro Molinari, Meana Sando, National Research Center of Women in the Government, Nicola Frangione, Nielsen Gavina, Nike-cooperativa di servizi ar.l (Oltre-Rivista bimestrale di informazioni locali), Orietta Nicolai, Oronzo Liuzzi, Paci Fausto, Paolo Barrile, Paolo Conti, Phosgenia, Piermario Ciani, Piero Barducci, Pinacoteca Civica-Pieve di Cento, Raimondo del Prete, Rita Vitali Rosati, Roberto Calabro, Roberto Migliussi, Roberto Zito, Ruggero Maggi, Sabrina Noncini, Salvatore Arelli, Salvatore De Rosa, Scuola Media Statale Aldo Palazzeschi, Serse Luigetti, Snank-y, Sommi Cesare, Spazioblobart, Techno Fetishism (Renzo Daveti), Tiziana Baracchi, Ubaldo Giacomucci, Umberto Stagnaro, Vittore Baroni, Vittorio Baccelli.
  - Japan, 1982-2004 (Box 8, Folder 2-12, Box 83, Folder 2, Box 84, Folder 5, Box 85, Folder 1,7, Box 86, Folder 1, Box 87, Binder 15, Binder 17, Box 89, Box 91, Box 94, Folder 4-7, Box 95, Box 97, Box 98, Box 99, Box 101, Box 102, Folder 14)
    Correspondents include: Akihiro Oshigami, Biwako Artists' Organization, BAO (Chido Honda), Dinn International, Forest Mail Center (Committee for Inner Trip Pavillion), Fumiko Tatematsu, Hiroko Midorikawa, Hiroshi Matsuyama, Hiroyuki Yumishita, Hitoshi Araki, Jun Kuramitsu, Kaori Inoue, Kayako Shin, Kayo Matsumoto, Kayo Nakamura, Kazunori Murakami, Kazuyoshi Takeishi (Aerial Print), Keiichi Nakamura, Kikuko Aono, Kikuko Ota, Kowa Kato, Kunio Yamayoshi, Makiko Masui, Masayo Kaneko, Mayumi Honda, Mukata Takamura, Noriko Ito, Reika Yamamoto, Ryoko Ono, Ryosuke Cohen, Seiei Jack Nakamura, Seiei Nishimura, Setsuko Kataoka, Shigeru Nakayama, Shigeru Tamaru, Shigeru Uesugi, Shin Oh!-No Dera, Shozo Shimamoto, Tadatoshi Fujino, Takayoshi Koike, Tamotsu Watanabe, Terrestrial Art Post Office, Teruyuki Tsubouchi, Tetsuya Fukui, Tomoyuki Nakade, Yoshio Nishimura, Yuki Kawasaki, Yuuko Funada.
  - Korea, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 13, Box 103, Folder 10)
    Correspondents include: Kum Nam Baik
  - Lithuania, 1989-1991 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    Correspondents include: Nekrasius Jonas, Saulius Sidlauskas.
  - Luxemburg, 2005 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    Correspondents include: François Frisch
  - Mexico, 1987-1999 (Box 9, Folder 3, Binder 17, Box 103, Folder 1)
    Correspondents include: Aarón Flores, César Espinosa, El Archivero, Eugenio Roque Mendoza Millán, Geraldo Yepiz, Mauricio Guerrero, Terra Candella (Harley).
  - Minsk, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    Correspondents include: Unidentified Correspondent
  - Myanmar, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 5, Box 103, Folder 2)
    Correspondents include: JM Rastorfer
  - Netherlands, 1981-2005 (Box 9, Folder 6-13, Box 10, Folder 1-2, Box 83, Folder 2,4, Box 84, Folder 5,7, Box 85, Folder 5, Box 86, Folder 3,7, Box 87, Folder 2-3, Binder 16, Binder 17, Box 89, Box 90, Box 92, Folder 1, Box 93, Box 96, Folder 3-4, Box 98, Box 99, Box 103)
    Correspondents include: A.D.Ecker, Aad van Deukom, Afzet, Arlette Boerlage, Arno Arts, Ars Electronica, Care for Mail Art Magazine, Cor Reyn, Ever Arts, Francke G. Bokellan, Gerrif Velthius, Henryk Gajewski, Ingrid van den Boogaard, Irma Boom, Jan Verschoore, Jenny De Groot, Joachim van Dÿk, Karen Holden, Ko de Jonge, Magda Lagerwerf, Makkom, Maya Gordon, Museum of Instant Images, Peter Below, Pier van Dijk, Rod Summers (VEC), Ruud Janssen, Sonja van der Burg, Spudz, Sunecho Lightline, World Wide Video Festival.
  - New Caledonia, 1990 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    Correspondents include: Daniel Maillet
  - Northern Ireland, 1990-1991 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    Correspondents include: Elizabeth Gaston, One Mail Order.
  - Norway, 1986-1990 (Box 10, Folder 5, Box 89)
    Correspondents include: Bjønnulv Evenrud, Guttorm Nordö.
  - Panama, 1983 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    Correspondents include: Manuel E. Montilla
  - Philippines, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 7, Box 88, Box 103, Folder 5)
    Correspondents include: Pedro Espinoza
  - Poland, 1984-1999 (Box 10, Folder 8-10, Box 69, Folder 1-2, Binder 16, Box 89, Box 90, Box 91, Folder 3, Box 93, Folder 2, Box 98, Box 99, Flat-file-folder 2 Right, Box 103, Folder 6)
    Correspondents include: Alina Gmur, Andrej M. Sobolewski, Andrzej Dudek-Dürer, Andrzej Wielgoez, Ania Gmur, Anna Lentowszcsyk, Anna Sochaj, Armii Czerwonej, Biuro Wystaw Artystcznych, Boris Zarzycki, Bozena Zachana, "Chatka Zaka", Darek Moch, Eveline, Grzegorz Dobrzycki, H. Agnes Zwara, Izabela Babula, Janusz Byszewski, Jolanta Swiderska, Kataryna Drelich, Kinga Ciukaj, Krzysztof Kowalski, Magda Suchanek, Malgorzata Sroka, ManiUsz Bak, Marcin Prus, Marek Skonieczny, Margaret Sroka, Matgorzata Piotrowska, Michael Krzyminski, Michalina Nowak, Oddzial Wojewodzki, Pawel Petasz, Raphael Nadolny, Remedium, Robert Rupociński, Roman Kaleta, Roman Muszynski, Roman Pietrek, Stainless Steel Louse, Tomek Zuch, Ursula Urbanowicz, Waclaw Ropiecki, Yach Paskiewicz.
  - Portugal, 1987-1992 (Box 69, Folder 3-4, Binder 15, Binder 16, Box 103, Folder 7)
    Correspondents include: Antonio Olaio, César Figueiredo, Emerenciano, Ernesto de Sousa, Fernando Aguiar, International Mail Art Salon, José Alfonso, José Eliseu, José Oliveira.
  - Romania, 1990-2004 (Box 10, Folder 11, Binder 16, Binder 17, Box 99)
    Correspondents include: Florean Museum, Ilie Eugen Sauchea, Ioan Hădărig and Balog Istvan.
  - Russia, 1994-2004 (Box 10, Folder 12, Box 86, Folder 6, Box 98, Box 103, Folder 8)
    Correspondents include: Dimitri Bulaton, Gik Juri, Harold Kaplan, Konstantin Malakhov, S.N. Stolarenko.
  - Saudi Arabia, 1983 (Box 10, Folder 13, Box 84, Folder 2, Box 103, Folder 9)
    Correspondents include: Wally Darnell
  - Scotland, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    Correspondents include: Transmission
  - Slovakia, 1993-1996 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    Correspondents include: Andrej Skribinek, Jaroslav Supek.
  - South Africa, 1991-1992 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    Correspondents include: Christo Van Der Schyff
  - Spain, 1983-2003 (Box 10, Folder 17-18, Box 11, Folder 1-2, Box 86, Folder 5,7,8, Box 90, Box 95, Folder 6, Box 103, Folder 11)